<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title># shon-bottle</title>
    <link>https://shon-li.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on # shon-bottle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Using &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/siegerts&#39;&gt;siegerts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/br&gt;© 2019 shon-bottle. &lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#39;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 23:35:35 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shon-li.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>bulletin</title>
      <link>https://shon-li.github.io/bulletin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 23:35:35 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shon-li.github.io/bulletin/</guid>
      <description>.readme. This gonna be a super long post, because I decided to put anything I want here. Yes some of it is in Mandarin, you can ignore it or find a way to translate it. I am too lazy to translate, and I somehow think, maybe It&amp;rsquo;s not bad to keep what it was in my mind.
I am taking this place as my friend, and I talk to my friend sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello</title>
      <link>https://shon-li.github.io/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 22:18:15 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shon-li.github.io/hello/</guid>
      <description>shon-bottle? Like a bottle in the sea, the information on this site is floating on the internet. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty intriguing to me that you are here. Because through this language this media, somehow we connected. It will be really a pleasure for me if you like something here.
So, really nice to meet you here, you can call me shon, or you will find my other names somewhere. I am now in New Zealand on a working holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shonScript</title>
      <link>https://shon-li.github.io/post/shonscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 18:00:22 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shon-li.github.io/post/shonscript/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an AutoHotKey script for the booking system of the hostel I am working in. Sorry, it can be tedious and confusing for you to read these code here directly. I am not so sure about why I post this here either. If you like reading it, it’s down there.
It can extract the booking information from the Outlook mail and the SiteMinder Channel Manager, then help to search and fill forms on the Backpack Online System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://shon-li.github.io/project/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 16:53:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shon-li.github.io/project/hugo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>