<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://shon.li/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://shon.li/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-14T20:48:44+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/feed.xml</id><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">杂讯 Noise</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/noise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="杂讯 Noise" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/noise</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/noise.html"><![CDATA[<p>我经常看到的一块大广告牌坏了，它原本应该显示广告的画面变成了不断闪动的灰白杂讯。我记得我小时候在电视上见到的这样的画面。好玩。可惜才过了一天这牌子就被修好了。搞笑的是过了大概一个星期之后它又坏了，然后我录下了一小段录像。</p>

<p>后来我在网上冲浪的时候突然看到了“娱乐至死”这样的内容。我记得它里面说到媒介就是信息。当看电视看视频取代了读书读文章变成了人们获取信息的方式，这种行为上的改变也会造成思考习惯的改变。</p>

<p>追逐快速的享乐是一方面，另一方面是专注思考一个内容的时间长度。我从小就觉得读书比较难，不只是当时老是碰到看不懂的字，我经常就看书看到一半就不想看了。有的学者就认为是因为电视节目的长度一般都只有一个小时左右。这就让人习惯了花这么点时间思考。现在手机上的短视频就更夸张了，几分钟一个新的视频。</p>

<p>快节奏的娱乐应该也有它的好处。但是它的坏处太危险了。我觉得人是很需要花长时间去想东西的。要是老是忘了或者静不下心那我觉得太可惜了。</p>

<p>所以就算这广告牌修好了，它上面播放的内容对我来说也大多只是杂讯。</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p lang="en">
  A billboard I often see is only displaying noise. I took a photo of it. I love seeing this 'malfunction' because it brings up my childhood memory of seeing noise on TV. Someone fixed it after only one day; but funnily, it is broken again in about one week. I recorded a video clip this time.
</p>

<p lang="en">
  While I was surfing the internet the other day, some content about amusing ourselves to death came up. There's a famous quote – "the medium is the message". The behaviour change of acquiring information from TVs and videos also changes our way of thinking.
</p>

<p lang="en">
  On the one hand, it is the fast paced entertainment. On the other hand, the change is how much time people spend on thinking. I found reading difficult at a very young age. Not only because I was stumbled on big words but also because of losing interest on the topic. Some researchers believe that this is a consequence of people being accustomed to watching TV programmes which are mostly about one hour long. The online videos and short videos nowadays are more worrying as they are only a few minutes long.
</p>

<p lang="en">
  I don't know what benefits are there in acquiring such fast 'happiness', but I am sure about the disadvantages from this habit. Taking time to process and think is essential for human beings in my opinion. It will be a pity if people often forget or always feel impatient.
</p>

<p lang="en">
  So the noise is always there, even if the billboard is fixed.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[我经常看到的一块大广告牌坏了，它原本应该显示广告的画面变成了不断闪动的灰白杂讯。我记得我小时候在电视上见到的这样的画面。好玩。可惜才过了一天这牌子就被修好了。搞笑的是过了大概一个星期之后它又坏了，然后我录下了一小段录像。]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">Buttercup 毛茛</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/buttercup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buttercup 毛茛" /><published>2024-12-09T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/buttercup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/buttercup.html"><![CDATA[<p lang="en">
  I found this little yellow flower in Albert Park, and I am told it's called buttercup. Later I found its Chinese name (<ruby lang="zh">毛<rt>máo</rt>茛<rt>gèn</rt></ruby>), but disappointingly, I have never heard of that name before.
</p>

<p lang="en">
  Something came into my mind about this flower – it's someone's signature I saw from a BBS. I heard that it is from a poem written by Rabindranath Tagore, but I cannot find the origin of it. Alas.
  <br />
  It goes like this:
  <blockquote>
  <p lang="en">
  You see it. You like it. Flowers bloom.
  <br />
  You don't see it. You hate it. Flowers bloom.
  </p>
  </blockquote>
</p>
<p><br />
我在公园里闲逛的时候看到了这个不知名的小黄花。后来我知道了它叫 <span lang="en">buttercup</span>。上网搜了之后知道了它的汉语名字叫毛<ruby>茛<rt>gèn</rt></ruby>。</p>

<p>这张照片让我想到我以前在一个论坛上看到的一个让我印象深刻的个性签名。好像那是泰戈尔的诗，可是我找不到原句。挺遗憾的。
<br />
那签名说：</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>你知道，你爱惜，花儿努力地开。<br />
你不知，你厌恶，花儿努力地开。</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I found this little yellow flower in Albert Park, and I am told it's called buttercup. Later I found its Chinese name (毛máo茛gèn), but disappointingly, I have never heard of that name before.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">麻雀过得还好</title><link href="https://shon.li/words/sparrows-did-well.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="麻雀过得还好" /><published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/words/sparrows-did-well</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/words/sparrows-did-well.html"><![CDATA[<p>我阳台斜对角的房子水管上挂了一大簇枯死的像爬山虎一样的植物。我最近注意到麻雀在那簇看起来像垃圾的枯枝里面筑了一个巢。可能这就是为什么每天早上五点左右我都会听到尖锐的麻雀叫声吧。可能是小麻雀们早上在练嗓子。</p>

<p>不知道为什么，我就是觉得麻雀特别可爱特别亲切。可能是因为我小时候见过他们吧，一些怀旧的感情就因此跟麻雀联系在了一起。当我看到麻雀的时候就会下意识的觉得自己也没有离开我曾经的家太远。麻雀还在。</p>

<p>大概是前年我在网上看到人说麻雀的数量在全球锐减。知道就连麻雀都要濒危了，我有点伤心。这几年在奥克兰的市区里到处都能见到麻雀让我很高兴。我听说新西兰有块地方是鸟的天堂，鸟儿们在那里是没有天敌的。虽然不知道鸟儿们是否会因此像现代的人一样疯狂繁衍伤害到自然里的其他生物，但是能知道这世上还有一块地方留给鸟儿们我感到些许欣慰。</p>

<p>我见过在马路红绿灯上的鸟窝，见过在停车场电缆架里的鸟窝。我可怜现代人的生活方式都没有留给其他动植物一块地方。我最近在看一本关于批评资本主义与当代人看待世界的观念的书。我觉得自己被点醒了。我觉得人类社会所谓的发展错了。因为这种发展不是互利互惠的，这种发展是以用更少的成本去换更多的利润为目的的。人们认为这世界是物质的，物质是没有生命并且可以被更“高级”的人随意使用的。所以我们就像癌细胞一样肆意地消耗资源，而我们所谓的发展却只是把原本的物质转化成对人来说有价值的东西。可悲的是我们世人的价值终究是离苦得乐。这所谓的乐是短暂的欢愉，是一阵大笑；是一种优越感；是一种未经慎重思考的损人利己的恶。</p>

<p>因为万事万物错综复杂，任何一个事物与其他事物都有千丝万缕的联系，所以人不是万物的主宰，也没有什么所谓的主宰。所有的东西都应该被理解被慎重对待。得到更多就会付出更多，就像质量和能量会守恒。当人类把自己生存所需的对象改造成漂亮好玩的东西之后，人类的生存就会变得困难。不过这种后果会到来得不那么迅速，以至于我们以为它不会到来。人类世界由权力驱使，权力是众人信奉或默许而产生的。能改变世界的只有我们的信念，当大部分人开始了解我们行为产生的不良后果之后，这种信仰就会渐渐失去它的权力。这种转变产生结果的过程是非常漫长的，漫长到我以为它永远都不会有结果。</p>

<p>可是无论结果如何，我相信做人要知道怎样是好的，并且做好的事。</p>

<p>我这样的观念是看<a href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=eWbqwcj9ALo">一个视频</a>了解到的。看过视频之后我决定看看视频里提到的书。如果 <span lang="en">Youtube</span> 打不开的话，这是哔哩哔哩的链接：<a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1p34y1E7GY/?share_source=copy_web">【<span lang="en">YouTube</span> 搬运】全球生态灾难的新解方：弃成长(<span lang="en">Degrowth) Jason Hickel</span> 《少即是多》</a>。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="words" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[我阳台斜对角的房子水管上挂了一大簇枯死的像爬山虎一样的植物。我最近注意到麻雀在那簇看起来像垃圾的枯枝里面筑了一个巢。可能这就是为什么每天早上五点左右我都会听到尖锐的麻雀叫声吧。可能是小麻雀们早上在练嗓子。]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Learning Jekyll</title><link href="https://shon.li/words/learning-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jekyll" /><published>2024-12-06T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-12-06T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/words/learning-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/words/learning-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally decided to use a static site generator. Tools like Jekyll once looked mysterious to me. After some irrelevant coding practices during my engineering study, I somehow feel more confident about learning to use them.</p>

<p>I picked Jekyll because it is the classic – it is widely used and GitHub Page supports it well. So it is a perfect entry level tool for me. I want to understand how it works, so I can have a good sense about how other similar tools work. Also, I hope I can make my website more interesting for myself.</p>

<p>In my initial thoughts, this website will not look like a blog at all, but I have to make baby steps, so I will do what I can to make small changes. It is better to make a kick start rather than stay at thinking. I will make frequent heartened changes to improve.</p>

<p>This post is intentionally written in English. Not to show-off my competency in this language, but a test on the layout design. After some trials and errors, I decided to take a chaotic approach on multi-language support. I will simply smash two languages together on my website. It is much easier to handle on a static site generator; also, it is how I process the languages in my mind. Words and characters swirl in my mind wiggling meanings and concepts. I know most people probably will not enjoy that, but for the ones who do – yay!</p>

<p>I found something annoying – the apostrophe, “’”. It is always rendered in full width which is what I hate to see. My HTML file encoding is alright; CSS text align is non-negotiable; I want to use Markdown to simply writing. <del>So I am out of solution for now. I will try to avoid typing that key when I am writing here.</del> Agh… Turns out I only need to use a backslash to escape that character when writing in Markdown. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">\'</code> gives '. Hahah… =D</p>

<p>I will add some of my understandings about Jekyll here later.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="words" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I finally decided to use a static site generator. Tools like Jekyll once looked mysterious to me. After some irrelevant coding practices during my engineering study, I somehow feel more confident about learning to use them.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">你想写一句吗? What Will Your Verse Be?</title><link href="https://shon.li/words/verse.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="你想写一句吗? What Will Your Verse Be?" /><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/words/verse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/words/verse.html"><![CDATA[<table class="two-columns">

  <tr>
    <td>
      读诗写诗不是因为它漂亮。<br>
      读诗写诗是因为我们是人。<br>
      人，有热情。
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
        We don't read and write poetry because it's cute.<br>
        We read and write poetry because we are members of the human race.<br>
        And the human race is filled with passion.
      </span>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td>
      医学、法学、商学、工程学，<br>
      都很高尚，<br>
      靠它们能延续生命。<br>
      但诗歌、美、浪漫与爱，<br>
      才是生命的向往。
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
        And medicine, law, business, engineering,<br>
        these are noble pursuits and necessary to sustain life.<br>
        But poetry, beauty, romance, love,<br>
        these are what we stay alive for.
      </span>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td>
      惠特曼的诗里写过，<br>
      「我啊！人生啊！…<br>
      首尾牵连的迷问啊；<br>
      永无休止的漠视啊…<br>
      愚昧漫天的城市啊；<br>
      这里还有什么美好？<br>
      我啊，人生啊。」
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
        To quote from Whitman,<br>
        "O me! O life!...<br>
        of the questions of these recurring;<br>
        of the endless trains of the faithless...<br>
        of cities filled with the foolish;<br>
        what good amid these,<br>
        O me, O life?"
      </span>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td>
      答案：<br>
      你活着。<br>
      有生命，有自我。<br>
      生命的大戏展开着，<br>
      你也能献诗一句。<br>
      你的人生就在那，<br>
      你也能献诗一句。
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
      Answer.<br>
      That you are here –<br>
      that life exists, and identity;<br>
      that the powerful play goes on and you may contribute a verse.<br>
      That the powerful play <i>goes on</i><br>
      and you may contribute a verse.
    </span>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td>
      你想写一句吗？
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
        What will your verse be?
      </span>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td>
      视频链接：
      <a lang="en" href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=-7OE6bDfM2M">youtu.be/-7OE6bDfM2M</a>
    </td>
    <td>
      <span lang="en">
        — <cite>Dead Poets Society</cite>
      </span>
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>

<div class="video-16-9">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-7OE6bDfM2M" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe>
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="words" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">波纹</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/ripples.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="波纹" /><published>2024-02-12T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2024-02-12T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/ripples</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/ripples.html"><![CDATA[<p>这是在阳光照射下，水滴落在一滩水上产生的倒影。画面里一圈圈的明暗变化让我看出了神。</p>

<p>我想着像一个个大圆球一样的波在扩散。波与波相遇后发生的神奇的事情。如果两个波持续不停，那么他们可以叠加出驻波……这一大堆我还不知道的事，有点好玩，也有点让我觉得我永远都不会弄明白。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[这是在阳光照射下，水滴落在一滩水上产生的倒影。画面里一圈圈的明暗变化让我看出了神。]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">闪光的沙子</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/shiny-sand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="闪光的沙子" /><published>2023-01-18T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2023-01-18T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/shiny-sand</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/shiny-sand.html"><![CDATA[<p>这是我跟朋友在 <span lang="en">Muriwai Beach</span> 玩时拍下的照片。那天阳光刺眼，海风微咸。我被地上闪着光的沙滩吸引了。那儿的沙颜色发黑，好像是因为富含矿物。</p>

<p>我很喜欢这张照片，画面里人是遥远的、渺小的；沙是亲近的、渺小的。我上次把它放到网站上的时候配了一句“我是沙子，我要闪光的”。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[这是我跟朋友在 Muriwai Beach 玩时拍下的照片。那天阳光刺眼，海风微咸。我被地上闪着光的沙滩吸引了。那儿的沙颜色发黑，好像是因为富含矿物。]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Nonchalant</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/nonchalant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nonchalant" /><published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/nonchalant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/nonchalant.html"><![CDATA[<p>I took this photo in the Auckland Zoo. This lizard stayed still the whole time while I was around. I see pride and disgust on its face.</p>

<p>This photo helped me to remember this word – nonchalant.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I took this photo in the Auckland Zoo. This lizard stayed still the whole time while I was around. I see pride and disgust on its face.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Orchy</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/phatom-of-moth-orchids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orchy" /><published>2021-08-21T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2021-08-21T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/phatom-of-moth-orchids</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/phatom-of-moth-orchids.html"><![CDATA[<p>This my friend Orchy. He was a lovely pink orchid. I wanted to take care of him, but sadly I didn't do well.</p>

<p>Anyway, I had a great time with him. To save myself some trouble, I will not take any new plants home again.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This my friend Orchy. He was a lovely pink orchid. I wanted to take care of him, but sadly I didn't do well.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="zh-Hans"><title type="html">水雾</title><link href="https://shon.li/photos/mist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="水雾" /><published>2021-06-30T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>https://shon.li/photos/mist</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shon.li/photos/mist.html"><![CDATA[<p>一栋居民楼上有建筑工人在用水枪清洗墙壁。原来一栋建筑想要保持漂亮的外观这么麻烦啊。</p>

<p>依着绳索飞檐走壁的人、在风中飞散的水雾、湛蓝的天，挺好看的。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[一栋居民楼上有建筑工人在用水枪清洗墙壁。原来一栋建筑想要保持漂亮的外观这么麻烦啊。]]></summary></entry></feed>